Awesome. So now that we have our code in here,
太棒了，现在我们已经有代码了
it's time for us to learn how to actually deploy our contract using JavaScript.
是时候来学习一下如何使用 JavaScript 来部署我们的合约了
This is going to teach us a lot about transactions and what's going on under the hood,
这将教会我们许多关于交易和底层机制的知识
and even what's going on under the hood in remix,
甚至可以让我们明白 Remix 的底层是怎样运行的
and remix, we usually just hit a compile button,
在 Remix 中，我们一般只用点击一下编译(Compile)按钮
and then hit a Deploy button. And that's really it.
接着再点击部署按钮，就行了
In JavaScript, we're actually going to create our own functions
在 JavaScript 中，我们需要自己创建的函数
that are going to help us do both of those.
以帮助我们完成这两项工作
And as I mentioned, this is the part of the course we're going to start working with JavaScript,
正如我之前提到的，这部分课程我们会使用 JavaScript 开展工作
and optionally, TypeScript if you like.
如果你想的话，也可以用 TypeScript
Like I said, all of these sections come with a TypeScript edition as well.
就像我说的，这部分所有内容都附带一个 TypeScript 版本
So let's set up our deployed out js script
那么让我们开始配置我们的 "deploy.js" 脚本
to actually deploy our simple storage dot soul.
以部署我们的 "SimpleStorage.sol"
So how can we get started here?
那么我们该从何开始呢？
Well, let's first learn how to run a script using JavaScript and Node J S.
首先让我们学习一下如何使用 JavaScript 和 Node.js 来运行一个脚本
So if you want to do a print line, or just print something out to your terminal,
如果你想要的打印一行，或者说打印一些东西到你的终端上
we can do something called a console dot log.
你可以做的是 "console.log"
And if I do console dot log, hi, I hit Save. And I open up my terminal.
如果我在这里输入 "console.log(hi)" 并且保存，接着打开我的终端
I can now run Node deploy.js. And it'll print out high
现在我可以运行 "node deploy.js"，然后它就会打印 "hi"
node is how we say hey, we want to run this JavaScript code using Node js.
"node" 就像是我们在说：“嘿，我们想要用 Node.js 去运行这个 JavaScript 代码”
Other languages you might be familiar with,
其它还有一些你可能熟悉的语言
sometimes we'll do Python, you know, deployed up py,
比如有时我们会用 python 运行 "deploy.py"
or Java, C deploy dot Java, you know, etc.
或是 javac 运行 "deploy.java"，等等等等
But with JavaScript, since the front end and back end JavaScript are different.
但对于 JavaScript 来说，因为前端和后端 JavaScript 是不同的
We run code on the back end with node.
所以我们在后端使用 node 来运行代码
And with JavaScript, you can do a lot of things that you'd see in something like solidity
在 JavaScript 中，你可以做到很多类似在 solidity 中看到的事
with a little bit looser have a structure.
但结构会显得有些松散
If I wanted to create some variable, I could say let variable equals five,
如果我要创建一些变量，我可以输入 "let variable = 5;"
this kind of similar into solidity like you and 256, variable equals five.
这就像是你在 solidity 中做的 "uint256 variable = 5;"
But in JavaScript, we use let or var or const.
不过在 JavaScript 中，我们使用 "let" 或 "var" 或 "const"
And then I can print this out, I can do console dot log variable. And I had saved
然后我可以把它打印出来，"console.log(variable);"，保存一下
JavaScript is optional on whether or not you actually want to have semicolons.
JavaScript 允许你选择是否带上分号(;)
Here, I think prettier, defaults to putting semicolons.
这里我认为默认放上分号会更好看一些
And we'll get rid of those in the near future
不过在不久的将来我们就会摆脱这些
in your terminal. Once you start typing the name of a file, if you hit tab,
在终端里，只要你输入了文件名字的开头，然后按下 "tab" 键
it could autocomplete the rest of the file name for you
它就会为你自动补全你的文件名
node deploy hit Tab, it'll autocomplete
"node deploy" 按下 "tab"，它就会自动补全
and if we hit enter, now, we get Hi, and then we get five.
现在我们按下回车，就会得到 "hi" 还有 "5"
Since this prints out Hi, and then it prints out five.
因为这里就是打印 "hi"，然后打印 "5"
JavaScript automatically starts with whatever code you have at the top of the file.
JavaScript 会自动从文件顶部的代码开始运行
So it does console dot log first and variable. And then this one as well.
所以它先运行 "console.log" 然后是 "variable"，最后是这一行
However, a good practice is to actually wrap everything you want to do in a main function,
然而，一个很好的做法是把你要运行的一切都打包进一个主函数(main function)中
and then run that main function.
然后再运行那个 main 函数
But what we could do is up at the top here,
我们要做的就是，到顶部这里
we'd say function, mean, add parentheses and some brackets,
输入 "function main" 加上括号还有花括号
a closing bracket at the bottom, and hit save for its auto format.
底部这里是一个右花括号，然后点击保存让它自动格式化
Right now, if we run this, nothing will happen,
如果我们现在就运行它，将不会发生任何事
because we've wrapped all of our code in a main function.
因为我们已经把所有代码都打包进了 main 函数中
So if I run it now node deployed to Jess, nothing happens,
所以如果我运行 "node deploy.js"，什么都没发生
because I need something to call the main function.
因为我还需要一些操作来调用这个 main 函数
So if I then take this, this main function down here, and I call main,
如果我选中这部分，把 main 函数放到这里，调用 main 函数
our jobs from code is actually going to say,
我们的代码实际上做的就是
ah, the first line of the script is actually this main function here.
啊，脚本的第一行实际是这里的这个 main 函数
So now if I do node deploy dot j, s,
所以如果我现在再运行 "node deploy.js"
it'll run high and five, which is what we want.
它就会运行出 "hi" 和 "5" 了，这正是我们想要的
Now, this is going to be the setup for most of our scripts moving forward,
这将是我们大多数脚本的设置
including the scripts that we write, when we get to hard hat,
包括我们用 Hardhat 写脚本的时候
however, there is going to be one major difference.
但这里还有一个主要区别
Instead of regular functions,  we're actually going to use something called async functions.
我们不使用常规函数，而是使用异步函数(async function)
And we're going to do something called asynchronous programming to do this.
我们要实现一种被称为异步编程("asynchronous programming")的东西
Now, if what I say next is really confusing for you
如果我接下来的话真的让你感到非常困惑的话
don't let it slow you down,
别让它阻拦你前进的脚步
feel free to go ahead and watch that JavaScript course to learn more about this.
请继续观看 JavaScript 课程以了解更多这方面的知识
But I'll also let you know, hey, this is an async function.
但我还是要告诉你一下，嘿，这是一个异步函数
Here's what we need to be aware of when working with it, okay.
这就是我们使用它时需要注意的地方，好吧？